# Tetiana Savaryn

# front-end / java developer



🔥 tetianasavaryn.com



t.savaryn@gmail.com



in linkedin.com/in/tsavaryn



**(**514) 826-7963

# **Professional Summary**

I am a front-end designer with java development experience and a passion for user interfaces. I'm excited about product solutions and development. I've been lucky to explore both back-end and front-end practices and my graphic design expertise has enriched my skills as a developer. I have been working in both end-to-end delivery and team project developments. Constantly training and improving my skills to achieve effective goals.

# **Technical Skills**

Coding	Development
HTML5	Java

CSS3 Spring Boot **JavaScript REST and SOAP** AJAX Database modelling

SQL **Bootstrap** Docker Design Angular UI/UX

Experience w/ React Adobe Photoshop

Git

WordPress Adobe Illustrator

Adobe InDesign

Adobe XD English, French,

Figma Ukrainian

### Education

#### **UX Design Professional**

Certificate at Google, 2022 - present

### **Server Side Applications & Services** development with Java

Concordia University, Montreal, 2021\*

### Web Development

Concordia University, Montreal, 2021\*

#### **Programming Fundamentals with Java**

Concordia University, Montreal, 2020\*

#### Infographic Design

LaSalle College, Montreal, 2020

#### **Business Administration**

Master's Degree at West Ukrainian National University, Ukraine, 2009

#### **Management Information Systems**

Bachelor's Degree at West Ukrainian National University, Ukraine, 2008

\*Graduated with A in every subject

# **Experience**

#### Infographic Designer, Image QA Specialist

GS1 Canada, Aug 2019 - present

Edited and retouched 3D Marketing images

Verified that all images respected all standards and requirements Conducted QA of product images and created label images

Prepared visuals for databank

### Wordpress Developer, Visual Designer

VicDi, July 2020

Prototyped and built WordPress website

Designed corporate brand, visuals and traditional prints

Integrated Google APIs

#### **Graphic Designer**

ARS, Ukraine, Aug 2013 - May 2016

Designed variety of marketing projects (magazines, billboards etc)

Created visual elements for websites

Designed corporate branding, visuals and traditional prints

# **Projects**

Java Developer Twitter Desktop App, Nov 2021

Built Java desktop application using avaFX and JDBC

Designed database, MVC architecture

Prototyped and implemented UI

#### Java Developer, Front-End Developer Teacher Portal, Mar 2021

Worked on models, DTOs and controllers

Used Hibernate to interact with database

Designed frontend with Thymeleaf, HTML, CSS and JavaScript Implemented SMTP email service

# Volunteer

Web Developer Ukrainian Orthodox Parish in Montreal, Apr - May 2022

Built website with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap Implemented internationalization with jQuery

Graphic Designer Svidomi, Mar - Apr 2022

Prototyped visuals for news media